Patrick A. Levell

email patrick@levell.tech • web levell.tech • LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/palevell

Profile:

Results-driven Systems Analyst / Developer, Business Analyst, and Bitcoin enthusiast with broad-based experience in enhancing system functionality and end-user productivity. Accomplished professional who has earned a reputation for consistently meeting and exceeding aggressive objectives. Effective communicator possessing excellent interpersonal and relationship-building skills.

Skills:

Programming	Libraries/Frameworks	Tools/Platforms
Proficient : C, Python, SQL, HTML, shell	Flask, Django, Pandas, SQLAlchemy	PyCharm, VSCode, WordPress
Experienced: Python, C++, JavaScript, CSS	Jekyll, Hugo, Node.JS	Git, Emacs, WebPack, JD Edwards / EnterpriseOne
Familiar: GO, PHP	Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, PyQt6, Tkinter	Apache, NginX, Docker, Heroku

Professional Experience

Programmer / Analyst:

- Using JDEdwards EnterpriseOne ERP forms and reports in combination with VB.Net and SQL Reporting Services in delivering optimized business solutions for National Accounts, Sales & Marketing, Warranty Services, and the Raymond dealer network
- Developing, designing, implementing, testing and maintaining the iWarehouseTM Fleet Optimization System, Raymond's first commercial software offering
- Working closely with executives, consultants, customers, suppliers, and end-users to define and refine requirements for Raymond's IT infrastructure
- Monitoring and troubleshooting issues in JDEdwards, data warehouse, and iWarehouse
- Developing strategy for streamlining operations by integrating business processes
- Supervising consultants and junior programmers working on a variety of projects

Computer Systems Analyst / Developer:

- Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom applications and reports in JDEdwards OneWorld ERP/MRP for Engineering, EMS/QMS, and other business systems
- Developing specialized reports & applications with JDEdwards, SQL queries, Excel, Access and VB/VB.Net/SQL Server
- Working closely with end users in defining and "fine tuning" requirements & creating documentation
- Training and supporting JD Edwards users in Finance, MRP, Sales, Purchasing, and Inventory modules

Freelance
Programmer,
Webmaster,
Database
Administrator:

- Mentoring bloggers, entrepreneurs, and Bitcoin startups in building and maintaining their online presence
- Performing as technical liason for clients with advertisers
- Administering customer databases
- Migrating web-sites to new servers

Related Volunteer Work

Social Media Advisor:

Electoral District Association

People's Party of Canada

London, Ontario (2019, 2021 elections)

- Building and managing social media presence on Facebook and Instagram for local candidates
- Promoting events for local EDAs and Maxime Bernier
- Promoting fund-raising and merchandise pages

Community Manager:

People's Party of Canada

Gatineau, Quebec (2019)

- Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom Twitter client
- Builiding a community for PPC candidates, volunteers, supporters, and critics
- Participating in "hashtag campaigns" with the following objectives:
 - to assist Maxime Bernier being invited to the national Leaders' Debates
 - to draw attention to the PPC platform
- Co-ordinating Twitter support teams for PPC candidates
- Developing specialized reports for Twitter users

Employers

Sole Proprietorship	London, Ontario	2012 to Present
The Raymond Corporation	Greene, New York	2007 to 2012
NUCOR Vulcraft – Florence	Florence, South Carolina	1997 to 2007

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems DeVry University, Chicago, Illinois Cumulative GPA 3.62 (Honours)

Integrated ERP Project Highlights

Custom applications with components in multiple environments, including Oracle EnterpriseOne, JD Edwards OneWorld Xe, and SQL Server, as follows:

iWarehouse A web application for fleet management and optimization; modules include the following:

Gateway:

ilmpact: impact monitoring (asset protection) iMetrics: vehicle and operator utilization iVerify: operator checklist monitoring

iBattery: battery utilization

Capital **Appropriations** An intranet application to automate the capital appropriations request process, replacing the

paper-based process

Request:

Exclusively ERP Project Highlights

Custom extensions or modifications on JD Edwards OneWorld Xe include the following:

Job Master Inquiry: A management tool in JD Edwards, summarizing customer account and project information in credit, sales, finance, engineering, and manufacturing systems, improving documentation and communication between departments; Created a user manual and 25-minute training video for this application using Snaglt, MS Publisher, and MS PowerPoint

Production Scheduler:

Fixed sales, purchasing, manufacturing, delivery date issues; linked to Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Input; resulting in fewer problems between Sales and Drafting Completed, Not Shipped (CNS) - the Finished Goods report - every nut & bolt in the plant is processed by this custom JD Edwards report—a critical piece of Vulcraft's month-end closing procedures; the Controller was using five other reports to get this information until CNS was fixed; month-end closing time was reduced by at least 20%; this report became an integral part of testing system changes in JD Edwards

Material Resource **Planning**

(MRP):

Report:

Troubleshooting, modifying, and performance-enhancing on this suite of batch applications, to reconcile sales, purchasing, manufacturing, and shipping dates, and reduce execution time & system resource requirements, as this is a resource hog

The "Havens"

A custom management report in JD Edwards, providing in-depth credit analysis of large and/or problematic customer accounts, with two sections—one for the customer, and one for top-level management

180-Day Weighted

A custom financial report in JD Edwards for calculating customer credit scores, based on their last six months of credit history

Average:

Over 40 Days: A custom financial report in JD Edwards for identifying overdue accounts

A custom JD Edwards financial (MRP) report for the Controller and Purchasing Agent, detailing current Deck

and projected raw material requirements Inventory:

Fab Schedule: The weekly production schedule from which most office activity stems; two specialized versions of this report created for Drafting and Shop Order; ties in to Manufacturing, Customer Service, Job Master,

Drafting, and Shop Order Inquiry screens

Drafting Inquiry: Added additional fields for tracking approval drawings, and signaling Production Scheduler whether drawings are in-process, out for approval, or back from approval; linked to the Job Master Inquiry and Shop Order Inquiry screens; resulting in providing Production Scheduler with up-to-the minute

information for scheduling purposes

Shop Order

Added additional fields for tracking bills of materials (aka. shop orders) through the engineering design Inquiry: program (outside of JD Edwards); linked to Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Inquiry screens; resulting in much improved traceability and fewer interruptions in Data Entry from Drafting and Shop Order, asking

for information

Shipping A management tool in JD Edwards combining bill of lading, sales, and shipping data for much improved reachability

Inquiry:

Daily A key custom JDE financial report used for invoicing, reported tons & dollars

Shipments:

SO - SF A custom JDE application for comparing what was sold to what was built & shipped; used primarily on

Compare: large jobs to show the dollar amount left to be invoiced

Re-price A custom JDE application for re-pricing jobs, typically used when design requirements change

Program:

Custom Application Highlights

Custom development using MS Excel/Access/.Net include the following:

Internal Audit A custom MS Access database application for managing internal audits of quality and environmental

Manager: management systems; generates checklists, audit questions, and audit reports

Inventory A custom MS Excel spreadsheet application to analyze supplier promised & actual delivery dates using

Tracking data from inventory and cost of quality spreadsheets; results delivered using charts, graphs, and pivot

System: tables

NUVU BoM A stand-alone application using VB.Net & SQL queries to transfer XML data from NUVU bills of **Transfer:** materials to the engineering design program, effectively getting NUVU (AutoCAD) to talk to the design

materials to the engineering design program, effectively getting NUVU (AutoCAD) to talk to the design program, written in FORTRAN, and still thinks it is running on punch cards; complete with installer and

auto-update feature for local and satellite sales offices

Shipping This was a tool to move the current delivery dispatches ("route-out") procedures from paper-based to

Route-out electronic; prototyped in MS Access and later integrated into J.D. Edwards

Prototype: electronic; prototyped in MS Access and later integrated into J.D. Edwards

NUVU Installer: A collection of shell scripts, HTML, and VB.Net programs to install NUVU on AutoCAD workstations,

including network security and administrative shares. All the users had to do to install NUVU was click

on a single web-link

Joist Input A front-end to the engineering design program, written in VB5 utilizing a SQL Server database instead of

Program: the old flat-files; object model created using Rational Rose; prototyping done in MS Access

Special Projects

- Created Twitter bots to help build a social media presence for a new political party in Canada
- Recovered stolen Internet domain name for a Colorado-based real estate brokerage firm; the investigation tracked the domain records down in Australia, and the owner in Spain; assistance was obtained from the International Trade Administration at the US Department of Commerce
- Served as Senior Lead Internal Auditor for six years. Led the team to make the transition from ISO 9001:1994 to ISO 9001:2000, which included leading the team that re-wrote the quality manual, and moving the quality manual from paper-based to an interactive on-line system, using MS Internet Information Server (IIS), SharePoint, and FrontPage
- Routinely served as corporate liaison with outside auditors of both our quality and environmental management systems

Cryptocurrency Project Highlights

- Owned & operated a Bitcoin mining farm, starting with two (2) FPGA miners, expanded to six (6) first-generation ASIC miners and a second-generation ASIC miner
- First-ever web-scraper to collect account information from the GBBG|BitBillions ¹ web-site